hello and welcome to the TR tutorial on
how to program a gript 2 so in our level
editor let's drag an NPC
down and make a
function on
created and in this tutorial I'm going
to teach you one of the single most
important things of all programming ever
and that's the loop and specifically a
for Loop
there's a lot of different kinds of
Loops but I'm going to be teaching you
the for Loop this time so type four
parentheses semicolon semicolon and
parenthesis then
brackets before the for Loop let's add
this. yellow is equal to
zero now what the for Loop is going to
do is that everything these brackets is
going to run over and over and over
Forever Until We Tell stop there's a few
ways to tell it the stop but we're not
going to do that this time so let's just
add this. yellow or plus plus it's going
to add it by one so every time it Loops
it's going to add Yellow by one so the
first Loop is going to add it by one
then it's going to go back up and go
back down and add another it's going to
go back up add another then go up
again so and then let's add a this. chat
is equal to
this. yellow the NPC is going to say the
value of yellow so we'll see it be we'll
see it as it
increases then let's add a sleep 0.5 so
it doesn't
increase too fast so that we won't even
be able to
see what the value is it's just going to
go up infinitely so let's
upload and as you can see it's looping
over and over and adding Yellow by one
and it's going to do that forever the
thing is about for Loops is that for
Loops have a limit to how many times
they can be looped other Loops don't
have some other Loops don't have this
limit but we're not going to into that
yet so the way to stop it from
looping is we can do it in two different
ways for one in the for Loop we can add
if this do yellow is greater
than 50
then in in
Brackets break so what break does is it
breaks the for Loop and just skips past
it and does whatever else is past the
for Loop we can also if we wanted to
have four Loops inside of other four
Loops or whatever other loop we want but
we're not going to do
that so it's going to Loop over and over
and over until yellows is greater than
50 or it's going to break
so once it's 51 it's going to break
let's
save and we'll wait for it to get
51 and now it just stops because it
broke the loop and it's not increasing
yellow
anymore so there's another way to make
it exit the
loop and that is by adding it into the
semicolons so let's take out yellow
here and here
and here and before the first semicolon
add
temp. n is equal to Zer this is creating
a new variable called n and making it
equal to zero and this is this variable
is going to break is going
to be destroyed once the function is
done but we won we won't need it then
and between the semicolons add temp. n
is greater than or equal to 30 and after
the last semicolon add temp.
n++ so the first parameter which is the
one before the first semicolon creates
the variable the one in the middle tells
it what must be true for the for the
loop to run and the last one increases
it or decre increases it by whatever you
want we can also just do equals temp. n
+ one we're just going to do
Plus+ so once it's equal to or greater
than 30 it's going to
break and here let's add this do chat
equals to n so every time it Loops n is
going to increase by one and once n is
greater than 30 it's going to it's going
to end the loop because because this
Loop only runs if n is less than or
equal to
30 so it's going to keep
increasing then it gets a 30 and just
breaks it breaks the
loop so I guess that's it for this
tutorial uh you have a faint
understanding of how to use the for Loop
now and you can do well I'll show you
more examples of what you can do next
tutorial so anyway bye